<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<speak>
	<amazon name="news">
		<break time="0.5s"/>
What's a subtle sign of low intelligence?
    <!--STORY 1-->
<!--<"Spinach969 · 9 days ago GoldStarryBravo!I'd Like to Thank..."/>-->
People who confuse their opinions with facts.
<!--The___canadian · 9 days ago GoldBravo!Helpful3-->
To add, people who think they know everything are generally pretty stupid.

Smarter people will defer questions to qualified and experienced individuals because they are acutely aware of their own limitations, and that's what helps make them smart. They're not scared to admit they lack knowledge in certain topics or fields. And they will learn from that more experienced person to add to their library of knowledge and experience.

Stupid people don't know they're stupid, they think they know everything, and won't seek out more experienced people and admit to their limitations, admit they don't know fuck all about certain things.
    <!--STORY 2-->
<!--Whysong823 · 9 days ago GoldBravo!Wholesome4Silver-->

The inability, or unwillingness, to change one’s opinion when confronted with new information. If a person just digs their heels in no matter how much they’re proven wrong on a given topic, they’re an idiot.


<!--a-midnight-flight · 8 days ago-->

I think it is also pride. Some people just hate being wrong and admitting to it. Even if they know they are.


<!--HerefoyoBunz · 9 days ago · edited 9 days ago-->

Well, opinon take time to change. Just because you are given new information, doesnt mean youre internally ready to shift your entire position. It usually takes time and a bit of self digging into a topic to change your opinion.

If your opinion ways as easily as you said, then you must not be very intelligent. Cause at that point you’re just following anyone who says it’s true. There’s alot of misinformation in the world so when someone isn’t something that they’re talking of, I presume them wrong, until I can see for myself. Otherwise mf could tell me a berry Im given isn’t poisonus, and then Id die because I ate it and turns out it was poisonous

    <!--STORY 3-->
    <!--ILTwisted · 9 days ago Gold-->

Not capable of understanding a nuanced point
    <!--divorcemedaddy · 9 days ago HelpfulTake My Energy-->

i think the complete opposite and there is no middle ground.
    <!--andytronic · 9 days ago Wholesome-->

Much of the time by my experience, it's them not WANTING to get the nuance of the point.

They get it, they just don't want to let go of their desired belief, even though evidence clearly doesn't support it.
    <!--kaeporo · 8 days ago-->

This is the big one for me. Being able and willing to break up the black and white of an issue into many different shades of grey, consider the relationship between those shades and with other colors, and then to form an opinion—based on evidence—without disregarding logical gaps, emotions, and the viewpoints of others shows immense intellectual strength.

But little concerning human psychology is 100% certain and even knowing this folks are still prone to reach unproductive conclusions, especially across society.

Are people here aware that troll farms are seeking to foster the exact opposite behaviors in reddit? They want to farm karma, spread favorable ideas, and break complex issues into more emotionally charged, polarizing sides.

    <!--STORY 4-->
    <!--International-Big170 · 9 days ago Wholesome-->

Buying a new car when you’re broke AF
    <!--User avatar level 2 Eyeamanon28 · 9 days ago-->

Dude yes…. I have a friend who is broke af, already barely making ends meet, what does she do a few months ago? Buy a TRUCK. When gas is $5 a gallon. Now she can’t even afford to take her kid to the dentist when he has cavities so bad his teeth hurt. Pisses me off to see, honestly.


    <!--User avatar level 2 ILikeLenexa · 8 days ago-->

For the last few years, it's been cheaper to buy a new car than a used one if you have to drive. Basically, take price / (200000-car mileage) / miles-driven-per-year.

Yeah, you have to keep it 17 years, but maybe they will. I ran the numbers on probably 150 cars before I bought mine and on a per year basis, was 70% of the closest used.

Cost-wise, if you can find a Ford Maverick at MSRP, and they turn out to not be badly designed, the price is amazing.
    <!--level 2 [deleted] · 9 days ago-->

Wow you just described my ex-rommate.

She would fight me on which toilet paper brand to get (5 dollar difference, that shit would last us 2 months) and cry she is broke as fuck and then go on three trips to europe and an ed sheeran concert

    <!--STORY 5-->
    <!--Midknight129 · 9 days ago Bravo!Helpful-->

They have a conspicuously small spread of skills for such a high-level wizard.
    <!--WastaHod · 9 days ago-->

All I need is fireball. If someone disagrees, fireball. If someone agrees, fireball. If someone is ambivalent, Fireball. You would not believe it but spell slots open at the end of the day, Fireball.

    <!--STORY 6-->
    <!--El_Dief · 9 days ago Wholesome-->

Calling something stupid because they can't understand it.

    <!--User avatar level 2 pearlie_girl · 8 days ago-->

This reminds me of a book that had advice on how to write a novel. It said if people can't understand what you're trying to say, they'll need to make a decision: "Am I stupid? Or is this novel stupid?" Well, dear reader, we know that we're not stupid... So therefore, the novel is definitely stupid.

"How not to write a novel" - a hilarious book with excellent advice.

    <!--STORY 7-->
    <!--Odd-Educator-4124 · 9 days ago -->
    Uses only empty buzzwords in their conversations. I've got a coworker who only communicates in phrases like "situational awareness" and "following breadcrumbs" and asks for meetings to "amplify our synergy."

This person was promoted beyond their level of competence and has no idea how to do the job.
    <!--Smeglougainess · 9 days ago-->

I do love the term situation awareness though. Some people truly lack it. This term was thrown around a lot in my military days.
    <!--LeeroyTC · 9 days ago-->

Not understanding analogies very well
    <!--User avatar level 2 SillyOperator · 9 days ago-->

I was going to say just this. I’ve spent a lot of time teaching people and I find that I personally learn best when I “scaffold,” or relate things to experiences I’ve had before. A lot of people seem to find that helps too.

Another thing is that today we are blessed with so many wonderful content creators who are great teachers and find ways to simplify super complex topics in a way that is accessible to the average person, assuming no background knowledge.

But I think a MAJOR sign of intelligence is recognizing that analogies, heuristics, and simplifications by any other name are limited. Those clever analogies to explain how vaccines work, for example, are only going to get you so far. And unfortunately there were a lot of people making arguments against vaccines in terms of analogies and discourse just started breaking apart.

Honestly I think this is a pretty dangerous thing. There are too many people out there who think speaking in comparisons and heuristics is “good enough” for incredibly nuanced and sensitive topics. See J. B. Peterson


    <!--STORY  8-->
    <!--insertnamehere912 · 9 days ago · edited 9 days ago-->
inability to accept new ideas. A truly intelligent person will listen and try to learn from something even if they believe it's bogus

Edit: I meant “a truly” not “I truly” I’m not like that I swear xD
    <!--wuttang13 · 9 days ago · edited 8 days ago-->

I have a slightly opposite example. Thinking new things are ALWAYS better. The bosses at my company are always pushing my department (IT) to implement new things (insert popular internet hot keyword) , without any background research first.

"We should move all are data into the Cloud. On premise servers are old news!"
"We should make X automated using AI and big data!"
Sigh...

<!--Edit: added stuff junktech · 9 days ago-->

That might also be a fear. Accepting a new idea or concept that can tear down a lot of things you've known your entire life, can have huge impact and implications on your mind. It's a tedious long process that take time and energy and not all have them.


    <!--STORY 9 -->
    <!--fettu-cine · 9 days ago Wholesome-->

Thinking their opinion/ perspective is also everyone else’s, thinking ‘no one does that’ because they don’t do that
    <!--ShiraCheshire · 9 days ago -->
A selfish idiot I used to know started responding to any health concern with "Well, you know, you're getting older..." This applied even if the person in question was a teenager still.

Why? Because he was getting up around middle age and that's what his doctors had started saying to him.
    <!--N8V_NVN · 9 days ago-->

I thought this too for many years. About 10 years ago, I learned that this is a trait of many people with autism spectrum disorder. For many people with ASD, they simply cannot fathom that someone would not like the same things they like/keep things in the same places. It is not an intelligence issue for them. It is the way their brain works.


    <!--STORY 10-->
    <!--pulpexploder · 9 days ago Helpful2Silver2I'll Drink to That-->
I've noticed that the dumber someone is, the dumber they assume everyone else is. Smarter people will often try to see the other side of an argument (assuming there's nothing else at play, like low self esteem). People with lower intelligence often assume that people who disagree with them are simply dumb because they imagine their arguments to be dumb.

    <!--KevinReems · 9 days ago-->

Likewise, people that lie, steal, cheat etc also tend to assume everyone else does or would given the chance.
    yojimborobert
<!--· 9 days ago · edited 8 days ago-->

Got in an argument on Reddit where they told me there was no way either of us would know something because we weren't scientists and because of that can't make any claims. When I corrected them that I actually was a published scientist that has taught for over a decade, they blocked me.

Edit: Since this has blown up, I just wanted add that I think scientific ignorance is the greatest threat to humanity and I'm open to any solutions. I dedicated a large part of my life to educating thousands of students, but I can't help feeling the problem is getting worse.



    <!--User avatar level 2 flekkzo · 9 days ago-->

It seems dumb people can’t grasp what average intelligence means, but well above average intelligence people are highly aware of the giant chasm up to the truly intelligent.

    <!--_calmer_than_you_r_ · 9 days ago -->
It goes back to curiosity.. It is more important to be factually correct than win an argument.
If someone is arguing with you, most intelligent people try to dissect what the other person is saying and want to figure out what they are missing in their own argument and fill in that gap to be correct moving forward, until they identify the error in the other person's argument and determine they are correct.

    <!--doublestitch · 9 days ago-->

People who do very little thinking themselves often worry that everyone else thinks even less. That tends to surface in one of two ways: they join conversations and assume someone else is much less informed than they are (such as assuming somebody picked up an idea from a recent meme, without pausing to find out it was really that person's college major); or else they don't recognize critique (such as reacting as if someone who disagrees with Ayn Rand must not have understood her).
    <!--STORY 11-->
    <!--GhostyKill3r · 9 days ago -->
Not understanding hypothetical questions.
    <!--IJzerbaard · 9 days ago-->

    Weirdest thing a fellow programmer has ever said to me is "I don't do hypotheticals". Hell, 90% of the job is thinking about hypotheticals. "What if this field had that value and then this method is called" etc .. that's the kind of thinking that a programmer is doing all the time. But not that guy, I guess.


    <!--KnightWhoSays_Ni_ · 9 days ago-->

"But like, what if..."

"Dude, that's literally never going to happen"

"No man, it's hypothetical"

    "Bro, who uses the word hypothetical you fkn geek"

    <!--STORY 12-->
    <!--SoggyDrywall · 9 days ago Gold2StarryHelpful3Wholesome-->

    Inability to see from another perspective.


    <!--RaNdOm_PeRsoNw · 9 days ago-->

     so true . They just can’t comprehend what you’re trying to convey.

    <!--Jhoosier · 9 days ago Heartwarming-->

    Maybe a better way to put it is, "an unwillingness to see from another perspective".

    <!--STORY 13-->

    <!--narfywoogles · 9 days ago HelpfulAll-Seeing Upvote-->

    Thinking people speaking a second language imperfectly means the person is stupid.

    <!--RHouseApoc · 9 days ago-->

I worked in a PT clinic where one of the therapists was taking on Spanish speaking patients so he could improve his Spanish. He wasn't great but he was definitely improving. It also allowed to him to widen his patient list so he could be more valuable to the team.

The other non-Spanish speaking therapists were making fun of him. It boggled my mind.

    <!--Leather-Owl4061 · 9 days ago HelpfulWholesome-->

    If I ever get frustrated trying to understand someone speaking broken English, I just remember that they're doing better at speaking English than I'd be at speaking their native language.

    <!--STORY 14-->
    <!--User avatar level 1 Comprehensive_Post96 · 9 days ago Gold3StarryOut of the Magic PortalHelpful7-->

    Lack of curiosity


    <!--User avatar level 2 b0nk3r00 · 9 days ago Table SlapI'm DeceasedSilver2ShockedBravo Grande!-->

    you ever had to train or work with someone who just has no desire to know anything beyond what you’re telling them or the why behind what they’re doing? Every instruction needs to be laid out in painstaking detail? If an issue arises, there’s no desire to understand why or attempt to fix it, they just error out and stand there waiting for instruction? It’s like programming a computer, but the computer is a human potato.


    <!--JohnWhoHasACat · 9 days ago -->
    This here is the one. And, like, being proud about not knowing it as well. Like people who want you to feel bad because you know a big word.


    <!--ButtFucksRUs · 9 days ago · edited 9 days ago Silver-->

I've had people get mad at me for wanting to look stuff up that the group was speculating on. Bro, we have almost all of the known information in our pockets and you're mad I want to spend 10 seconds to consult with it?

"Why do you always look stuff up?"

Fuck off, Nick.

Edit: To clarify, these aren't intellectual debates. This is Nick calling everyone in our friend group idiots because he thinks that green is a primary color on the color wheel and doubling down when we show him it's not and he tells me how much I suck for looking it up.

Also, arguing about what time certain fast food restaurants close.

    Edit 2: I can't believe that Nick created so many accounts to say that green is a primary color.


    <!--STORY 15-->

    <!--genghisKHANNNNN · 9 days ago Eureka!Helpful -->
    I think people are confusing signs of low intelligence with signs of being an asshole.
    <!--ElectriFay · 9 days ago-->

Sometimes people are assholes simply because they cannot logic their way out of it. :-(

    <!--STORY 16-->
    <!--effectivewall99 · 9 days ago Silver-->

Thinking that they’re always right/not admitting when they’re wrong.

    <!--BarfingOnYourFace · 9 days ago Silver-->

What if I’m an idiot who always admits to being wrong?
<!--User avatar level 2 KMFDM781 · 9 days ago-->

If you don't argue unless you know absolutely that you're 100% right, you will never be wrong in an argument.

    <!--STORY 17-->

    <!--hobbitdowneyjunior · 9 days ago · edited 8 days ago WholesomeTake My Energy-->

Inordinate anger at animals that do things they don't like

    Edit: Thank you for the awards! And to everyone who thinks this is about mosquitoes, you need to relax. If I meant bugs I would have said specifically bugs.

    <!--thebutta · 9 days ago Gold-->

    YES like bro your dog doesn't speak English. Stop just yelling at it.

    <!--re_Claire · 9 days ago-->

    My ex was like this. Claimed to love all animals but actually if one didn’t immediately adore him he’d be angry. Especially if it didn’t listen to him or did something he didn’t like. He also used to say things like “you think you’re always right” and then I’d google it and confirm that I was indeed right and he’d be furious. Like no, I’m not always right at all but I am right about this one thing and maybe you’re just not that smart?? He was an ass


    <!--dissapointing_poetry · 9 days ago-->

    Using too many words to explain a simple concept or story. “Dumbing it down” actually requires some hardcore brainpower at times

    <!--RackDiscprin · 9 days ago-->

    I’ll be the first to admit, I had no idea how hard dumbing things down was until I had children. Like, how do I dumb down how to pour cereal? They ask so many questions that are amazingly simple for me to know, but super difficult to explain.

    <!--bluenooch · 9 days ago · edited 1 day ago-->

Read “Thing Explainer” by Randall Munroe. You can see how hard it was to describe the operation of a Saturn 5 rocket using only the 1,000 most common English words.

    Edit: corrected Randall’s last name. Edit2: Corrected it again because I’m a dumbass.

    <!--STORY 18-->

    <!--JacksSenseOfDread · 9 days ago-->

    Starting at a certain conclusion and then working backwards to justify the logic.


    <!--STORY 19-->
    <!--Sharp_Impress_5351 · 9 days ago Gold-->

    Getting sucked into the "easy and fast money" scheme du jour. MLMs, NFTs, Pyramid Schemes, "investments"... you name it.

<!--Plaguerat18 · 9 days ago WholesomeAll-Seeing Upvote-->

I think it's worth mentioning that a lot of this stuff preys on vulnerable groups of people, for example with regards to MLMs, they largely target young mothers from conservative cultures with no tertiary education who have been disconnected from the labour force for a long time. MLMs market themselves as a way for such people who often feel alienated from the professional workforce to be employed outside the domestic realm and to work with people like them. Imo joining an MLM is a very emotional decision rather than a logical one, which is why it can seem stupid when you don't resonate with those emotional needs because on paper it just looks like a bad deal.

    <!--User avatar level 2 AdjNounNumbers · 9 days ago-->

Whatever, dude. Beanie Babies are coming back big time. All I gotta do is hodl... It's only a loss if you sell

    <!--STORY 20-->

    <!--dallas_087 · 9 days ago Gold-->

Mocking or Making fun of people who want to learn more or get a higher education.

    <!--xetgx · 9 days ago Helpful-->

    To piggy back on this: people who mock others who are intelligent but weren’t able to get a higher education. Assuming that they can’t be intelligent unless they followed the traditional education path.


    <!--STORY  21-->
    <!--NoEngineering5990 · 9 days ago · edited 8 days ago Silver-->

Obsessing over an IQ score

    Edit holy hell, that blew up! I've never woken up to 90+ AskReddit notifications

    <!--DavinaCole · 9 days ago-->

Yes! I had a guy in college who kept bragging he has an IQ of 110. I was like dude….
    <!--STORY 22-->
    <!--Ori0un · 9 days ago-->

Judging an idea or concept based purely upon some people who follow it, and not the concept itself.

For example, believing veganism as a concept is bad just because you had a bad experience with a vegan.

    It's subtle because people do this all the time with everything. Making arguments that mislead others by only showing the bad apples to support an illusion that the thing as a whole is also bad.


    <!--OrangeJuliusthekid · 9 days ago-->

The inability to think from another’s point of view is a sign of low intelligence. Not understanding that people operate so differently from one another. Or that different people go through different walks of life, so they act and react differently.

    Close minded is the best way I can describe it. Someone who refuses to think about how others have approached a situation.


	</amazon>
</speak>
