<speak>
<amazon:domain name="news">

<break time="3s"/>
STORY 17
<break time="3s"/>

<!--squirrels33 · 11 mo. ago · edited 11 mo. ago-->

As an English teacher, I’m probably biased, so take my opinion for what it is.

    That said, I can often identify a brilliant student by the way she or he uses written language. It’s hard to explain. It’s not just vocabulary, and it’s not the concepts communicated in the writing; it’s the fullness and maturity of the writer’s voice (which encompasses the aforementioned and then some). The piece of writing often sounds like it could not possibly have been authored by the student.


<!--Crabscrackcomics · 11 mo. ago-->

    Reminds me of this one science teacher I had in 6th grade, but in a more negative light. I turned in a project we had to present to the class, used data, some
    simple math, and just a bit of explanation. After I did my project and walked up to her at the back of the class to get my grade, she gave me a C because, I quote exactly, "It looks too well written to be by a student." Ignoring how she couldn't even be bothered to check the edit history (we were using google docs..) it
    was the biggest confidence booster I had during middle school. Still kind of in shock that her first thought to a well written presentation is "this kid is copy
    and pasting!".. Man now I wonder if she still works there. (She was a little crazy though, as in... threw someone's headphones across the room and broke them because she got mad they were using them. They were Beats.)


<break time="3s"/>
STORY 18
<break time="3s"/>

<!--die-squith · 11 mo. ago-->
My paternal grandma is really intelligent, I think. She went to secretarial school in the 1950s but never really worked, so I wouldn't call her highly educated or anything. But I think she could have gone far in higher education if she'd attempted it.

I'll explain something to her, and ask her if I'm making sense. She's 90 years old - I wouldn't be at all surprised if I said something that went over her head from time to time. But she doesn't miss a step. Whenever I describe a situation or concept to her and ask her if I'm making sense, she will repeat the thing I said back to me, using different wording and her own examples to prove she absolutely understood. I don't know many other people who do that.

    She also is happy to change her stance on anything when presented with new information. And a lot of times she'll bring it up again months later and thank you for showing her a new perspective. (She isn't just swayed by me because I'm her granddaughter, she's the same way with everyone else I've ever seen her interact with.)

    <!--tl;dr - -->
    More people should be like my 90 year old grandma, who is not a dumbass and actually listens to people.

</amazon:domain>
</speak>

