<speak>
<amazon:domain name="news">
<break time="3s"/>
STORY 12
<break time="3s"/>
<!--SwimmerAutomatic2488 · 11 mo. ago · edited 11 mo. ago GoldHelpful2Wholesome5Silver3-->

People who use analogies to explain concepts to others. It’s a form of code-switching and integrating concepts on the fly is a clear indicator someone is both socially and conceptually intelligent.
    Edit: As many have pointed out, not all analogies are helpful or make sense to others. So a useful analogy that creates an “ah-ha!” moment for someone is a wonderful thing. An analogy is an association; a mental process of connecting an idea or thing to a relatable image for someone who can then “see” and digest the initial representation.

Not using analogies doesn’t mean someone can’t be intelligent. And “Social Intelligence” doesn’t mean social ease and charisma, it means an awareness that one's own understanding and experience often has to be translated in ways that others can relate to.

<!--User avatar level 2 Crunkabunch · 11 mo. ago Wholesome-->

Kind of related - I tend to find that the most intelligent individuals are able to explain difficult topics/concepts in a manner that is easy for many to understand.

<!--pseudocultist · 11 mo. ago -->

    I was struggling to explain 3D printing to my elderly neighbor without visual aids. My younger friend pipes up, <break time="0.5s"/> "Pretend you're sculpting a castle out of hot glue, think of how you'd do it, layer by layer." I was so awed at her ability to pull a simple analogy that would work for the old woman. But my friend is a polyglot,a translator by trade, so I shouldn't have been surprised I suppose.


<break time="3s"/>
STORY 13
<break time="3s"/>

<!--AngelicCinnamonBun · 11 mo. ago Helpful-->

I think intelligent people are more willing to calmly debate/discuss, rather than argue. Like, you explain to them why you disagree, and they listen to you and ask further questions about your viewpoint before offering a different perspective; as opposed to an unintelligent person, who would just resort to insults when other people disagree with them.


<!--Spencer2091 · 11 mo. ago -->
  Someone had a different political view as me, and I was trying to genuinely listen to them.
 Then they made fun of me for going to U.V.U unlike their "top 100 school" and I knew it was hopeless.

<!--TheNerdNamedChuck · 11 mo. ago -->

I actually love arguing, I find it fun to bring up evidence to make counter points against my opponent. I'm friends with a guy and we argue (debate?) at least once a week most times on Apple vs Android and Apple vs the competition in general. We've done this for nearly a year and not a single insult has been used. I do believe he's smarter than me but I still love being able to debate things without being insulted. Unfortunately I usually forget this is a pretty special thing and get destroyed by some asshole who doesn't know shit on a subject but can insult you for days.


</amazon:domain>
</speak>

