<speak>
<amazon:domain name="news">
What is a subtle sign that someone is really intelligent?

<break time="3s"/>
STORY 2
<break time="3s"/>

Talking to people as if they're intelligent at their level and without being condescending or even letting on that it's lower than their level.

I used to work with a doctor, Tom Howard, and the day I realized he was a genius was the time he guessed every single condition a patient of mine had, based on minute pieces of information about him!

I was struggling with a fault on a new machine that we had at work. In the canteen one of the senior engineers got talking and the machine problem came up. He was from a different department and had never seen that machine before, but in 5 minutes of talking about it he made a suggestion of what was going wrong and how to fix it permanently. He got it spot on.


To this day I have no idea how he did that. He must have built that machine in his head, imagined how it would work at a deeper level, what could go wrong with it and how to stop that operation going wrong.

It was supernatural!


<break time="3s"/>
STORY 3
<break time="3s"/>

They are curious about everything.

To be intelligent you need to be knowledgeable and you cant be knowledgeable if you are never curious.

You can memorize a bunch of random facts and repeat them, that’s knowledge. But knowing what to do with that knowledge, how to apply it, how to make sense of it, is what I think real intelligence is.

Richard Feynman captured that mindset perfectly in his book.


<break time="3s"/>
STORY 4
<break time="3s"/>
When they explain something, they make you feel intelligent.

This! So underrated. Smart people never bother showing off that they are smarter. Instead they end up pulling up the IQ of everyone around them in the room a few notch, and do it in a manner that noone feels belittled.

Edit: upon reading the below comments and some further thoughts.. I agree that people who geniuses often have shitty social skills and are often megalomaniac and assholes. Regular above average intelligent people know better than showing off. But off the charts iq kinda geniuses are often assholes. Smart vs wise as DeviMon1 said

</amazon:domain>
</speak>

