<speak>
<amazon:domain name="news">
<break time="1s"/>
STORY 10
<break time="1s"/>
<!--doublestitch · 11 mo. ago · edited 11 mo. ago Big Brain Time-->
They apply knowledge from one realm into a new and relevant situation.

    For instance one person described a situation (might have been on Reddit) where they were a new assistant in an academic research lab and fixed a snag that stumped all the senior researchers including the professor. The team was trying to video record their project using a strobe light and their footage wasn't working as planned.

    When no one else made progress at diagnosing or solving the problem, the most junior individual spoke up and suggested that the strobe could be out of phase. They remembered that video typically records at a rate of 24 frames a <w role="amazon:NN">minute</w>second [thanks for the correction], and explained that along with suggesting a change to the strobe's flash rate so it would coincide with the recording.

This worked. And it really raised up that individual's reputation within the group.

Inwardly they were almost embarrassed about the source of this knowledge. They had a gaming hobby back in high school, and had taken some video footage of that, and discovered the standard frame rate while playing around in editing software.

But they remembered that detail years later and realized it made a difference in a completely different context.

That, is, intelligence.


<break time="3s"/>
STORY 11
<break time="3s"/>

<!--paidshill29 · 11 mo. ago Helpful4Silver2I'll Drink to ThatTake My EnergyAll-Seeing Upvote-->

They can genuinely consider an idea which opposes their worldview without necessarily accepting it.

<!--GrayGeo · 11 mo. ago HelpfulSilver-->

    I've got a bone or two to pick with Aristotle, but I can vibe with his misquoted <break time="0.5s"/> "It is the mark of an educated mind to be able to entertain a thought and not accept it."


<!--herpaderpadont · 11 mo. ago-->

This is key. I hold onto my beliefs until I am showed different and then evaluate to see if my belief holds true.

Don’t take things at face value. “I’ll get back to you on that.” is a good response.

</amazon:domain>
</speak>
