<speak>
	<break time="1s" />
			Reddit, what's your most "I'm with the Boomers on this" opinion?

			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY1" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Unique_Football_8839 &#183; 3 days ago-->

Touchscreens in cars are a fundamentally bad idea and physical buttons (or similar controls) need to be brought back.

Distracted driving is at an all-time high. Touchscreen controls literally require you to take your eyes off the road and can create a longer time of inattention due to their complexity.

I have an old-ass car with physical controls. I can do dang near anything (radio, climate control, etc.) without taking my eyes off the road and in much less time.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Ron497 &#183; 3 days ago-->

Add in the number of monster trucks that are the size of a tank and the number of ridiculously souped up chargers and mustangs, and we are seeing record numbers of car related fatalities in the U.S. Speed and size and distraction kill. And we&#8217;re too busy trying to get half of America to comprehend that climate change exists, so even though it&#8217;s election season, nobody talks about distracted driving or our obsession with car culture in America.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY2" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--guythatbedont &#183; 3 days ago WholesomeTake My Energy-->

I want a human customer service operator not an automated operator or chat bot.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--EndHlts &#183; 3 days ago -->
Dude for real, I hate having to go through 5 minutes of menus just for it to connect me to a person anyway, and then they have to transfer me 3 times. What purposes does it even serve?User avatar
<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--level 3 JoePizza22 &#183; 3 days ago-->

The purpose is to annoy people to the point where they give up and decide it isn't worth it, that way the company has to deal with fewer problems and spend less money. Also a lot of people are idiots and will call customer services about things that could be solved in 5 seconds by Googling or reading information on the website.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--mikebikeyikes &#183; 3 days ago-->

I lost my passport in china, every time I called the embassy I had to wait at least 15 minutes to actually talk to a person. Took 7 weeks to finally get them to make me one and I spent tens of hours just talking to that robot menu. I hate it
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--thor454 &#183; 3 days ago-->

And then that person hardly speaks your native language and also couldn't afford or even have whatever service or product you're calling about coupled with zero shared life experiences make for some really daunting issues. Like if my problem wasn't a strange one off type situation I'd have easily figured it out via the internet or bull shit automation. Like once I bought an airline ticket for like 8 months out. Flight got canceled and they issued a refund finally by sending it to the bank account I used to purchase the tickets...I had closed that account and switched banks months prior they told me to just willy nilly ring up the bank as if I hadn't tried that. Bank said it'll be returned as they have no record of me at this point the customer service said its the banks problem and they wouldn't do shit. Because they said all you have to do it call the bank . as if they fucking know how the American banking system works in Bangladesh
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY3" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--anonymouslyinvisible &#183; 3 days ago Helpful2WholesomeSilver3-->

I don&#8217;t need a subscription for everything. No you don&#8217;t need my phone number or email just let me buy my shirt and get the fuck out of the store
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--stedun &#183; 3 days ago Helpful-->

I simply reply &#8220;no thanks &#8220;
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY4" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--PropellerHead15 &#183; 3 days ago GoldBravo!Wholesome2Silver-->

Certain things shouldn't require you to download an app and/or create a whole account, including:

    Ordering food in a restaurant

    Paying for parking

    Buying something online

    Sending a parcel
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--chickachickabowbow &#183; 3 days ago-->

			I'll throw in buying concert tickets (thanks TicketBastard!) especially since they got rid of tickets entirely and you get in by scanning a code on your phone. I have a huge collection of ticket stubs that all bring back various memories of concerts, but the most recent one I went to has absolutely nothing physical to remind me of the experience (the hell I'm paying 50 bucks for a t-shirt or 200 for a poster).

			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY5" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY4-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--EternityLeave &#183; 3 days ago &#183; edited 3 days ago HelpfulWholesome2Silver2Take My Energy2-->

Music in bars is too loud.
(Edit to add that I've been a touring musician and live sound technician. I love music but it actually sounds better at lower volumes, and I want to be able to hear it in to my old age)
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--level 2 lucid00000 &#183; 3 days ago-->

			I want to find just one bar where I can talk to my friends without screaming
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--User avatar level 3 erike1666 &#183; 3 days ago-->

			Whaaaaaat?!
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--RuneTek2b &#183; 3 days ago You Dropped ThisHelpfulTake My Energy-->

HE SAID HE WANTED TO TALK TO US WITHOUT SCREAMING!
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--lowtoiletsitter Cake day &#183; 3 days ago HelpfulSilver-->

WHO'S LEAVING?
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--User avatar level 3 hecaete47 &#183; 3 days ago-->

I worked in a store recently that had control over the music volume. Myself and coworkers always had to go over and turn it down bc the store manager kept turning it up way too high. If I can&#8217;t fucking hear the customer, I can&#8217;t help them. And if the customer can&#8217;t fucking hear me, they can&#8217;t be helped. Like??? Leave music at a normal enjoyable level.
<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Project_XXVIII &#183; 3 days agoi-->
Weddings, parties, stores, just about everywhere. If we&#8217;re going to a concert, then crank it. If the music is to &#8220;enhance the experience&#8221;, and instead it&#8217;s just drowning it in noise pollution, then there&#8217;s a failure in execution.

			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY6" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--mercurialpolyglot &#183; 3 days ago Wholesome-->

Screw fast fashion, my clothes should be made to last.

I&#8217;m not rich so it&#8217;s unavoidable, but I&#8217;m willing to spend extra on clothes that aren&#8217;t made of plastic and I do my best to repair my damaged clothing instead of throwing it out.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Rainbow_mama &#183; 3 days ago -->
			There&#8217;s a documentary on the company shein. I&#8217;m sorry I can&#8217;t remember the name of it but it&#8217;s about the working conditions of the people that make those clothes and it&#8217;s horrific. Also the environmental impact from fast fashion is so much higher than anyone would think.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--SandpitMetal &#183; 3 days ago-->

My wife and I were watching a Canadian TV show once where they go undercover to investigate different things (I forget the name, but they'd look into anything sketchy) and had an episode about SheIn and other fast fashion companies like them. Not only are they horrible working conditions and awful for the environment, but many of their clothes also contain toxic chemicals and heavy metals (and not the good ones like Iron Maiden, either). Basically by wearing their clothing, you are poisoning yourself.
<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Rightinthepiehole &#183; 3 days ago-->

I want to buy a pairs of jeans that will last more than 2 years. Levi's have not been lasting more than a year for me lately.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Baron_Von_Awesome &#183; 3 days ago-->

Go Wrangler. Less expensive than Levi's and last quite q long time.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY7" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--mostly_browsing &#183; 3 days ago GoldHelpful2Wholesome2Hugz-->

TV is getting too dark. Not emotionally - it is visually too dark and I can&#8217;t see it
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--kittenmommy &#183; 3 days ago Hugz-->

    Not emotionally - it is visually too dark and I can&#8217;t see it

And it's way too quiet until it's suddenly way TOO LOUD!
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--sandersonprint &#183; 3 days ago-->

			Or the 'background' music is louder than the dialogue
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--level 4 kittenmommy &#183; 3 days ago-->

			That too. We watch everything with subtitles now.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--DenTheRedditBoi7 &#183; 3 days ago Starry-->

Too dark and too quiet. I swear we have to turn the volume up like twice as loud as we have it normally to watch Yellowstone.

Better believe the commercials have plenty of volume though...
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Far_Reward4827 &#183; 3 days ago -->
There's almost no show I watch anymore without captions on
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY8" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Pollowollo &#183; 3 days ago GoldHelpfulWholesome3Faith In Humanity Restored-->

Not everything needs to connect to the internet or have an app attached to it. I just want my fridge to keep shit cold, I don't understand why we have to bring WiFi into this situation.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Alleonh &#183; 3 days ago-->

My fucking TOOTHBRUSH has an app. Why? WHY???
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--PhysicsRefugee &#183; 3 days ago-->

Omg what is the app supposed to do??
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--User avatar level 4 Alleonh &#183; 3 days ago-->

I have no idea. I never downloaded it. I just tried to look it up (oral b smart series) and it looks like a game that maps out your progress (so basically encourages you to keep brushing the full 30 seconds per &#8220;zone&#8221;). It&#8217;s completely redundant because it vibrates to let you know 30 seconds has passed. Who is going to pull out their phone, load the app and watch every time they brush???

That being said it does have a little box that mounts by your sink with a smiley face that frowns disapprovingly at you if you brush to hard. With a clock. So I guess that&#8217;s nice? I don&#8217;t fucking know man, the batteries went dead in it about a year ago and I never replaced them&#8230;. Just typing all this made me realize oral b is cramming way too much shit in their brushes.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--level 5 PhysicsRefugee &#183; 3 days ago-->

That is a very over engineered toothbrush
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--chupmacabre &#183; 3 days ago Spit-takeHelpful-->

I literally just talked a friend out of getting a &#8220;smart&#8221; automatic litter box with an app and shit. The price difference was $300 more than just a &#8220;regular&#8221; automatic scooping box and you get .. what? Notifications that your cat just took a shit?
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Typical_Ad_210 &#183; 3 days ago Helpful3SilverNarwhal Salute-->

My nose does that for free
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Aayin &#183; 3 days ago GoldTable SlapI'm DeceasedHelpful3-->

My indicator was always dig dig dig dig...DIG DIG DIG DIG DIG DIG (x5)...dig dig, followed by a flying leap out of the litter box, spreading the litter like shrapnel.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Killentyme55 &#183; 3 days ago-->

Don't forget the long pause.

"Welp, guess he's finally done."

			DIG DIG DIG DIG DIG....
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--ZebraUnion &#183; 3 days ago -->
Also don&#8217;t forget the nails on chalkboard

			&#8221;..screeeee! ..scree ..screeeeee!&#8221; as they scratch at the walls searching for more invisible litter to bury their poo with.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--NW_Oregon &#183; 3 days ago-->

			And then when you go check you see that all they managed to do was flick a few pieces of litter on top of their turd and have left it completely unburied to stink up the room.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY9" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--No_Seaweed6739 &#183; 3 days ago-->

			Basic home appliances (fridge, washer/dryer, etc) do NOT need a touch screen
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--gimpisgawd &#183; 3 days ago-->

			I just moved into a new place. The microwave his wifi compatibility, I don't know what it's for or for to use it but it's an option.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--ibnQoheleth &#183; 3 days ago-->

			Hacking your microwave so I can give it a virus that means your food is either slightly undercooked or overcooked, but never just right.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--cerulean47 &#183; 3 days ago-->

I hate my oven so much. It's a Jenn-Air fancy pants dual oven, stainless steel with a color touchscreen.

When I open the door, steam comes out and covers the touch screen.

Sometimes it's just that I can't use the touch screen at that point until I wipe the steam off.

Other times the whole oven shuts down claiming there's some kind of internal fault. It thinks multiple areas of the touch screen are shorted together. Which I guess they kinda are.

And the one time I used the self cleaning feature it cooked the internal electronics and I had to have the entire board replaced.

			Then there's the fact that everything you do with the touch screen has animations so it takes me 30 to 40 seconds just to turn the oven on and set the temperature.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--wasteland44 &#183; 3 days ago-->

			I learned from the castiron subreddit that the self cleaning function seems to break a lot of ovens. It is totally absurd.
<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--teemo03 &#183; 3 days ago-->

It's like stop adding touchscreens and just give me a functioning ice maker lol
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--KlausVonChiliPowder &#183; 3 days ago Gold2Wholesome-->

			One that dispenses Sonic ice
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY10" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--claytondb &#183; 3 days ago Wholesome3SilverTake My Energy-->

			Sometimes it's faster (and easier) to just plug something in, instead of dealing with bluetooth connectivity. There's something nice about knowing how to get it connected and being able to physically connect/disconnect.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Mithrawndo &#183; 3 days ago -->
			The same applies to networking: WiFi is not a panacea, and it's very much worth your while doing some cabled networking if you actually value your networked experiences.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--hunter54711 &#183; 3 days ago-->

Most petty thing that annoys me is almost all smart TVs have Ethernet ports but almost every single one is limited to fast Ethernet which is 100mbps, meanwhile the wifi can go much faster. I value my networking experiences and that's why I want to have a wired connection. In addition a TV is probably the best case for a wired connection, it's something that never moves and is static and is already tethered to the wall for power.

			Your options for above fast Ethernet is WiFi or buying an Nvidia Shield Pro. How much can gigabit Ethernet cost in 2022?
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--MaikeruGo &#183; 3 days ago &#183; edited 3 days ago-->

			To add to this some cars won't let you manually select the input device from the stored BT devices if you get going faster than 5 MPH and don't drop back down to a full stop&#8212;and in a number of cars these systems have issues automatically selecting the right device if multiple devices are stored as connections. Also, the audio quality is usually better when using wires and there's no annoying weirdness of the car's BT supporting one set of codecs and one device OS supporting another set that only overlaps the car's set with the worst possible codec of the group.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--level 2 Phenomenomix &#183; 3 days ago-->

			I would blow someone for next cheap iPhone to have a headphone jack again. Sick to death of getting on the metro and finding out my headphones are near dead
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY11" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Kanedi4s &#183; 3 days ago HelpfulSilver-->

			If you&#8217;re walking on a crowded sidewalk, get off your fucking phone it&#8217;s not the job of other pedestrians to avoid you while you make your vlog. Awareness of your surroundings is important.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--ravenschneid &#183; 3 days ago -->
Also respect the norms.

			Seeing people filming their dance moves in a cemetery and in front of the Vietnam memorial wall. Holding up travelers' spots because they have to shoot pics from 100s of angles.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--ChanceZestyclose6386 &#183; 3 days ago-->

			I've seen people stand in the middle of a stairway, blocking people going up and down the stairs just to do something on their phone. The lack of awareness of people around them is horrible.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY12" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--shearsntears &#183; 3 days ago GoldHelpfulWholesome2Silver-->

			tipping has gotten out of control- coming from someone who relies on tips for income. it hurts people who actually should be getting them because now people are extremely agitated about any and all tipping. i was just at a music festival and the guy who exchanges your cash for drink tickets (not even the person who pours the beverage) had an ipad with tip options starting at 18%
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--PlopPlopPlopsy &#183; 3 days ago-->

I'm always confused by the option to tip at the SELF SERVE frozen yogurt place. Wtf...

			I'm also suspicious that it won't even go to the cashier, it'll just go to the owner because it's from my debit card....
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--alexrbrodie &#183; 3 days ago-->

			I went to a bar recently and the bouncer had an iPad with tip options for the entry fee. Tipping should be reserved for products/experiences that require service or process like wait staff, baristas, bartenders, etc.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Healthy-Scientist846 &#183; 3 days ago-->

			When We Were Young? They wanted a tip for EVERY THING. The guy at the merch tent who didn't even stop his conversation with another employee to hand me two t-shirts from next to him (literally didn't have to take 3 steps) asked if I'd like to leave a 25% tip!?

			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY13" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--wheresmychin &#183; 3 days ago Bravo!WholesomeAll-Seeing Upvote2-->

			When you&#8217;re in a public place you should respect others around you but not being disruptive with your behavior. For example, not playing music on your phone without headphones while on a bus, in a restaurant etc.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--95_Random &#183; 3 days ago -->
Or those MFers who walk around having loud ass phone conversations on speaker in stores.

			Makes me want to slap that shit out of their hands.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--apatheticcanteloupe &#183; 3 days ago-->

			Back when I worked in retail, customers would ROUTINELY be having a phone conversation on speaker while I was using the bathroom. I never felt bad about the loud flushing toilet going off or the even louder hand dryers. It&#8217;s super distasteful to me to be on the phone, on speaker, in the bathroom. Some of the conversations I heard were just &#128563;
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--RichardBonham &#183; 3 days ago Silver-->

I&#8217;m a primary care doctor and I&#8217;ve had people pick up a call in the middle of an appointment.

It used to grind my gears, but now I just get up, leave the room and go see the next patient.

			I leave enough of a note so that when I come back about 20 minutes later I can just walk back in and pick up exactly where we left off. It&#8217;s usually hilarious.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY14" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Ghostleeee &#183; 3 days ago GoldBravo!To The StarsWholesome2-->

			I&#8217;m not downloading a fucking app to use your menu
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--brilliantpants &#183; 3 days ago &#183; edited 3 days ago StarryBravo Grande!-->

And I don&#8217;t need a goddamned app for every website, shop, or restaurant I visit. Please just put your menu and hours on a normal website and stop tying to clog up my phone.

			Edit: And Have a REAL website, not a Facebook page or Instagram account. Those might be good in addition to your website, but if the only way I can place an order is through your Insta DMs, just fucking forget it.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Roach_Coach_Bangbus &#183; 3 days ago -->
"This is best viewed in our app"

			No, it's not.

			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--jordancolburn &#183; 3 days ago-->

			This, but for everything. 75% of apps should just be a standard responsive website. It would load faster, be usable across more devices, less work for the dev teams to maintain a presence on all the app stores and update. I really think most of the time and effort put into apps is to make them "sticky" and just more present on users devices, at the cost of just about everything else.

			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--lexologist &#183; 3 days ago &#183; edited 3 days ago-->

I work at a restaurant as a host and recently failed our secret shopper because I asked &#8220;how many menus?&#8221; Instead of &#8220;would you like menus or the QR code on the table?&#8221; Most of the time when I do remember to ask, people just look at me confused and say &#8220;3&#8221;. It&#8217;s great.

Edit to add: we don&#8217;t have the feature where you can order through the QR code. Just the menu.

Secret shoppers are lame and when I initially &#8220;failed&#8221; I didn&#8217;t know we were supposed to ask this, so I didn&#8217;t get written up or anything.

Our menus are at the front and it&#8217;s the hosts&#8217; job to get the right amount before bringing the guests to the table, which is why we ask how many are needed. This isn&#8217;t necessarily the way all restaurants work, but this is what I was trained to do.

			I am hoping to be promoted to server soon (they told me before the year ends) and if they don&#8217;t by January, I will quit.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY15" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--iamapizza &#183; 3 days ago HelpfulTake My EnergyLOVE!-->

I work with software/security and the more I learn in this field, the more it makes me allergic to "smart" home devices. I'm convinced they are for people who don't know how they work, which is what they are banking on. And these devices are most certainly not smart.

			Along the same line for home appliances... if it needs an app to operate, it's a shitty device and you're making a mistake.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--level 2 lynnwoodblack &#183; 3 days ago-->

			I considered getting into software security and a common theme I found was "if security were an afterthought... that would be a huge improvement".
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--stealthkoopa &#183; 3 days ago All-Seeing Upvote-->

			Hey wiretap, what's a good recipe for pancakes?
<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--User avatar level 3 scorpiogre &#183; 3 days ago HelpfulWholesomeSilver-->

This is awesome I laughed, so did my wife and our refrigerator!!
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY16" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--buckyhermit &#183; 3 days ago GoldHelpfulSilver-->

I like physically owning the movies you love.

I have friends who love the movie and watch it on Netflix whenever they can...... and then Netflix removes it. And if it's a rare find, then you might never see it again. Owning a physical copy means you get to keep it and cherish it forever.

And if you're on a plane, where the movie options can sometimes be garbage? A handheld BluRay player is your answer.

			Also I love the artwork of BluRay covers. Another reason to have a physical copy.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--corran450 &#183; 3 days ago-->

Older Millennial here. I still love physical media, especially video games. If you have the disc/cartridge, they can&#8217;t take it away from you and make you pay to play it again. As long as you maintain your hardware, at least.

Besides, it&#8217;s nice to have a physical manifestation of what you have exchanged your hard earned money for.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY17" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--talag1ga &#183; 3 days ago &#183; edited 3 days ago Helpful2WholesomeSilver2-->

Things aren&#8217;t made like they used to be. Everything you buy now is so cheaply manufactured. Even high end furniture uses cheap particle board and crappy joinery. We bought a pretty high end couch a few years back and it&#8217;s barely holding together.

Edit: thanks everyone for commenting and thank you for the award! I&#8217;ve been on Reddit since 2008 and have never had a comment get this much action
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Birdhawk &#183; 3 days ago Wholesome-->

			I miss appliances you could fix just by hitting it a few times.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--level 3 uncreativegarbage &#183; 3 days ago GoldTable SlapSilver2-->

I too love percussive maintenance
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--eggy_delight &#183; 3 days ago-->
			I love this example

At work most of our clients are .1%, our last house had $400k worth of furniture. The table was 1 1/4 thick but all the boards were laminated 3/4 and 1/2 boards, not to mention it came pre warped.... guess the planeride overseas took its toll. The legs were this cylinder made of wood with gappy joints. When I knocked it was hollow, crazy to think this is a structural piece.

On my time off I make furniture that's more traditional. It's frustrating to know how much that table must've cost but I'll die struggling to sell furniture that'll last longer than me



			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Ving_Rhames_Bible &#183; 3 days ago-->

I worked in a cabinetmaking shop for a bit as a general laborer, my first month or so was helping the actual experienced cabinetmakers put together a 1/4 million-dollar custom basement bar for a client. Tables, boothes, door casings, wainscotting, decorative columns, the bar itself, all absolutely gorgeous woodwork that looked like something out of a cathedral, way nicer than you'd find in a generic pub. Even the plywood for the drop ceiling tiles was some fancy expensive type.

I always figured that's how the really rich people do things when it comes to home furnishings, all customized like that. Guess not.



			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY18" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--level 1 hankbaumbach &#183; 3 days ago HelpfulSilver-->

A lot of products were made better in the past.

Pyrex is a prime example but there's thousands more.

			Planned obsolescence as a consequence of prioritizing quarterly profits over customer satisfaction is another nail in the coffin of this current version of the economy we live in.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--stealthkoopa &#183; 3 days ago -->
			Craftsman tools, used to be something you could hand down, it not the case any more
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--FormalMango &#183; 3 days ago-->

When I moved into my own home, my dad gave me a big stack of his old tools. It&#8217;s always a huge nostalgia hit for me whenever I have to fix something, because I can remember handing him that exact same hammer, spanner, or screwdriver etc when I was a little kid.

			But more than that - everything is at least 40 years old, and it all still works.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY19" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->

			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Ancient_Wisdom_Yall &#183; 3 days ago Gold2Stonks RisingWholesome-->

			Most features in cars should have buttons. Want to turn on your heated seat, button, not scroll through three screens.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--remotetissuepaper &#183; 3 days ago All-Seeing Upvote-->

But the have the disclaimer screen not to use it while driving which is a totally reasonable expectation /s
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--8.8k CM_DO &#183; 3 days ago-->

			Ye let me just park every time I need to adjust the temperature or want to change radio stations
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Newfor2022 &#183; 3 days ago-->

			That reminds me of a police video I saw years ago when Tesla's were appearing on the roads, one got pulled over for some sort of "illegal modifications" or distracted driving law after the cop saw the giant screen the driver was looking at. The driver was like no, this is straight from the factory how it comes and convinced the cop there was no infraction.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--PositivityBear &#183; 3 days ago-->

My favourite is my dodge doesn't allow you to type stuff in while rolling. So anytime my wife needs to put in directions to something, she has to text me, then I pull my phone out, type in my password and then she forwards the address to the car lol.

			Let's cancel this basic functionality so you must do this junky work around.
<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--seaofflames &#183; 3 days ago-->

This is just bad UI. Screens require us to take our eyes off the road - a recipe for disaster. Buttons and dials? Only need one hand. Eyes on the road. I miss car radios with buttons and dials.
<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--02K30C1 &#183; 3 days ago-->

Honda changed their radio volume control back to a button a few years ago because so many customers complained about the touch screen
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Round-Rice908 &#183; 3 days ago-->

			Give me a backup camera, power windows and bluetooth connectivity. That's it. Leave the other BS off and take $8k off MSRP, thanks.

			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY20" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--WinterBanana89 &#183; 3 days ago &#183; edited 3 days ago GoldSilverTake My Energy-->

Having to create a username and password to join just about anything online is a royal pain in the ass

Good gravy this got way more attention that I was expecting. I will check out Password Manager seeing as it is highly recommended.

			For the record-I often see boomers much more fed up with computer requirements that require jumping through hoops more than younger generations. I don't think younger generations love these irritating requirements but if anyone feels this is not a boomer opinion I really don't have the energy or care enough to argue
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--zawica &#183; 3 days ago-->

			Make sure you have one upper case letter, a number, and a symbol, and it has to be 12 characters long, and it can&#8217;t be a password you&#8217;ve used in the last month, and we will make you reset your password every month, forcing you to constantly come up with new passwords you will never remember!
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--chameleiana &#183; 3 days ago-->

			Don't forget that even if you've ticked the box to remember you, we'll randomly log you out anyway.
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="STORY21" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--STORY-->
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--FirstPianist3312 &#183; 3 days ago &#183; edited 3 days ago StarryRocket LikeWholesomeSilver6Take My Energy-->

You should really put your phone down when you're out to eat with people. Maybe it's because I grew up with that rule but I know when I'm getting lunch with a friend or something I find it incredibly irritating when they're on their phone

Edit: holy shit my first award??
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--User avatar level 2 CADE09 &#183; 3 days ago-->

			My dad does this all the time. Can be having a full conversation with him and he'll just pull his phone out and start completely ignoring you. Drives me insane!
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Squirrel_McNutz &#183; 3 days ago-->

			Yeah this one is rough. Funny enough I feel boomers do this as much as anyone. They&#8217;ve gotten absorbed too
			<break time="0.3s" /><mark name="COMMENT" /><break time="0.3s" /><!--Athompson9866 &#183; 3 days ago-->

			My 68 year old mother guilts the shit out of me and my family to come visit and not just &#8220;leave immediately after you eat,&#8221; but the whole entire time we are there, everytime, she is on her iPad or phone playing games. Last time she was actually in my sons room playing Lego Jurassic world in the ps4 almost the entire time we were there

	</speak>